

+8801715045590

🖄 raihan.gafur.49@gmail.com

/raihanthecooldude

? /raihanthecooldude

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:

C, C++, Java, C#, PHP, Laravel, Node.js, React.js

Web Languages:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript

Database:

SQL Server, MySQL, MSSQL, PL/SQL, Oracle

Problem Solving:

Codeforces, UVA, LightOJ

Area of Interest

- Cyberpsychology
- Human Computer Interaction (HCI)
- Blockchain
- Software Development

Achievements

- Achieved Dean's List Honors from American International University – Bangladesh
- Achieved scholarship from American International University – Bangladesh
- Achieved scholarship from Government on talent pool section based on Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) exam
- Won fund from YOUNIFI in 2015 (A project by BYLC collaborated with University of London) for a social welfare plan and organized that project named Project Donto with more than 100 orphans in a child home called LEEDO's
- Champion in ICT Olympiad (Senior Level) at BUP Techsurgence 2019
- 2nd Runner Up in ICT Olympiad (Senior Level) at JU CSE Fest 2019
- Champion in Photography Contest at Govt. Science College Scientist Mania 2014
- Champion in Photography Contest at Business Genius Bangladesh 2014
- Runner Up in IQ Test (Senior Level) at Notre
 Dame National Science Festival 2013
- Was an Olympic Day Runner in Olympic Day Run 2012

S. M. Raihan Gafur

As a motivated individual. I would like to build up my career as a successful software engineer for pursuing a challenging career in an organization where enthusiasm, excellent environment and motivational factors will help and support me to utilize my knowledge and expertise for professional development.

Academic Qualifications

2016 - 2020 **BSc. in** (

BSc. in Computer Science and EngineeringAmerican International University - Bangladesh
CGPA: 3.90 out of scale 4.00

2014 - 2015

Higher Secondary Certificate
Notre Dame College, Dhaka
GPA: 5.00 out of scale 5.00

2012 - 2013

Secondary School Certificate
BAF Shaheen College, Tejgaon, Dhaka
GPA: 5.00 out of scale 5.00

Experience

Porte Chai

Business Development Executive | Mar 2020 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Generating innovative ideas for business development
- Researching about organizations and individuals online (specially on social media) to identify new leads and potential new markets.
- Develop targeted marketing and promotional strategies
- Plan and execute activation and campaigns promoting company features
- Pitching about the product and services to the investors

Additional Responsibilities:

I am also working as a backend developer in Porte Chai

- Developed the admin dashboard of Porte Chai using node.js and MySQL
- Developed the backend and functionalities of Porte Chai website using PHP and MySQL

American International University - Bangladesh

Software Developer Intern | Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

Responsibilities:

- Develop a portal management system module for intern students of CS department using react.js and laravel
- Design and develop the full web view of the system using react.js

Extra Curriculum Activities

AIUB Computer Club

President

Feb 2020 - Present

- Organized Webinars
- General Secretary
 Sep 2018 Feb 2020
 - Organized ICCA 2020 alongside with CS Dept.
 - Organized AIUB Cyber Gaming Fest 2019
 - Organized Jarvis Intra ACC Carnival 2019
 - Organized 7th Foundation Day of ACC
 - Organized AIUB CS Fest 2018
 - Organized many workshops and seminars
- General Member

Sep 2016 - Sep 2018

- Volunteered as lead in all events at AIUB Gaming Fest 2018
- Volunteered as lead in many events at AIUB CS Fest 2017
- Volunteered in AIUB CS Fest 2016

BASIS Students' Forum AIUB Chapter

- ConvenerMay 2020 Present
 - Coordinated NASA Space App Challenge 2020 in AIUB

Notre Dame Nature Study Club

- General Secretary
 Jan 2014 Jan 2015
 - Volunteered in 5th NDNSC National Nature Festival 2013

Notre Dame Debating Club

- Senior Programming Officer
 Jul 2013 Aug 2015
 - Volunteered in NDDC National Debate Festival 2013
 - Took part in debates in different debate competitions

Hunan University of Humanities, Science and Technology (HUHST), China

Cultural Exchange Delegate | Oct 2019 - Nov 2019

Responsibilities:

- Learn the cultures of China to have a progressive spiritual life and clear life goals
- Learn the different cultural activities as a delegate in the university
- Show the cultural differences between culture of Bangladesh & China in front of other delegates and hosts

Academic Projects

Food Comparison System - Foodo's | Web

Comparing or listing any food item with restaurant names based on desired price range of full Dhaka City or any specific area.

2 People Group Project | Dec 2018

Github: https://git.io/JfiZV

Platform and Tools: Laravel, HTML5, CSS3, Mysql

Responsibilities:

- Develop the views using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript
- Develop the database and models using laravel framework

2 People Group Project | Oct 2018

Github: https://git.io/Jfo38

Platform and Tools: Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Mysql

Responsibilities:

- Develop views using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript in express.js
- Design the database and develop models using node.js
- Develop some of the controllers using node.js

2 People Group Project | Aug 2018

Github: https://git.io/Jfo3l

Platform and Tools: PHP, HTML5, CSS3, PL/SQL, Oracle

Responsibilities:

- Develop the front-end using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript
- Design the database
- Develop the back-end of the website to fetch the data from the database in PHP

University Portal and VUES System | Desktop

An University (i.e. AIUB) management system where students can see their grades, their teacher's name of any course, given notes, notices and also can chat to other student. Faculties can see their student's information, give grades, notes and notices. Admin can add faculties, students and other admins to the system

4 People Group Project | Mar 2018

Github: https://git.io/Jfo3C

Platform and Tools: C#, Mssql

Responsibilities:

- Develop the full student entity such as it's class libraries, repositories and GUIs
- Develop an internal system where students can see their grades, semester wise CGPA, total CGPA, teacher's name of any course, given notes, can also download them.

Reference

Dr. Dip Nandi

Associate Professor

Director

Department of Computer Science

American International University-Bangladesh

Email: dip.nandi@aiub.edu
Phone: +8801755619344

Abhijit Bhowmik

Associate Professor
Department of Computer Science
American International University-Bangladesh

Email: abhijit@aiub.edu Phone: +8801926836045

MD. Saef Ullah Miah

Director, Prochito ITS

PhD Researcher, Universiti Malaysia Pahang

Email: md.saefullah@gmail.com

Exam Routine and Seat Plan System | Desktop

An University exam seat plan and routine system where the students will get their routine and seat plan in their personal account of the university portal. And course teacher can upload exam routine and seat plan.

3 People Group Project | Sep 2017

Github: https://git.io/JfXMp **Platform and Tools:** Java, MySQL

Responsibilities:

Develop classes and entities of the system

Develop the backend and GUI of the system

Video Streamer | Web

A video streamer where any videos played automatically like a digital billboard

Solo | Sep 2018

Github: https://git.io/JUhIL

Platform and Tools: Javascript, JQuery

Ball Game | Desktop

A console ball game where a player needs to throw a dart to a ball without collision, if the darts collide, the game will finish.

4 People Group Project | Oct 2018

Github: https://git.io/JUhTV

Platform and Tools: C++, GLUT

Responsibilities:

• Develop the game logic

Ticket Printer | Desktop

A ticket printer where user can give a design of a selected size and get the pdf formatted tickets

Solo Project | Jun 2018

Github: https://git.io/JUhmX

Platform and Tools: C#